Guide to the French Revolution and Napoleonic Period Manuscripts, 1752-1882 (bulk 1788-1815)
French Revolution and Napoleonic Period Manuscripts, 1752-1882 (bulk 1788-1815)
- Autograph manuscripts
  - Fa-France, Convention Nationale (Box 5)
    - France. Armée d'Italie, 24 Febr. 1796; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - France. Armée d'Italie, 18 June 1799; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - France. Armée de la Moselle, 29 June 1794.; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 31)
      ALS in French, signed by Barère, Billaud-Varenne, Carnot and Prieur
    - France. Armée, 10e bataillon de l'Isère, 1796; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - France. Armée, 1er bataillon du Maine-et-Loire, 16 August 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 33)
      ALS in French. Certificat d'officier pour Malibert
    - France. Armée, 1er bataillon de Valenciennes, 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - France. Garde Nationale de Bordeaux, 16 August 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 35)
      ALS in French. Leave/furlough to the Citizen Enselme
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, 1790; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 36)
      ALS in French.
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, May 1790; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, September 1790; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, August 1791; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, Nov. 1791; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 40)
      ALS in French. Brevet
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, 30 June 1792; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 41)
      ALS in French. Dischage for Jacques du Breuil, signed by, e.g., Pétion, with a significant seal of Paris
    - France. Garde Nationale de Paris, 1. Oct. 1792; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - France. 27e Division Militaire, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 43)
      ALS in French. Form in blank: oath of allegiance to the Constitution
    - France. Armée des Pyrénées-Orientales, Dec. 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - France. Assemblée Nationale Constituante (Committee of Investigation)., 18 Sept. 1790; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - France. Assemblée Nationale Législative, 16 Dec. 1791; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - France. Assemblée Nationale Législative, 6 Sept. 1792; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - France. Bibliothèque nationale, April 1804; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 48)
      ALS in French. Receipt for an acquisition through gift
    - France. Comité de législation, 4 August, 1795; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - France. Comité de législation, 12 Sept., 1795; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - France. Comité de surveillance révolutionnaire (section Guillaume Tell, Paris), January 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - France. Commissaire de la Marine X to ?, 1797; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - France. Commissariat des Postes, to the Minister of Finance, January 1804; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - France. Commissariat des Postes, to the Minister of Finance, February 1804; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - France. Commission des Armes et Poudres [Capon], 4 June 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 55)
      ALS in French, approved and signed by Prieur and Lindet
    - France. Commission des Transports, 16 July 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - France. Conseil des Cinq-Cents, 17 January 1799; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - France. Conseil des Cinq-Cents, 11 Juky 1796; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 58)
      ALS in French, plus a second letter
    - France. Conseil Executif Provisoire, 30 July 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - France. Conseil Executif Provisoire, 16 July 1795; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - France. Consulat de France à Hamburg, 13 Dec. 1796; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - France. Consulat de France à New York, 1797; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 62)
      ALS in French. Certified copy of a medical certificate for Hauterive, issued and signed by Consul Rozier, with an interesting engraved vignette
    - France. Convention Nationale, January 8, 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - France. Convention Nationale, May 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - France. Convention Nationale, June 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - France. Convention Nationale, June 1793; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - France. Convention Nationale, 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - France. Convention Nationale, July 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - France. Convention Nationale, Febr. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - France. Convention Nationale, 1795; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - France. Convention Nationale, 10 March 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 71)
      ALS in French: passport for Salicetti (Représentant auprès de l'Armée d'Italie)
    - France. Convention Nationale, 10 March, 1794; 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 72)
      ALS in French: passport for Servière (Représentant auprès de l'Armée de Sambre-et-Meuse)
  - France, Convention Nationale (Box 6)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Législation, registre des arrêtés, 16 July 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Législation, registre des arrêtés, 17 July 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Législation, registre des arrêtés, 18 July 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 25 April 1793; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 18 July 1793; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, n.d. [1793]; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 6)
      ALS in French [cut: signatures of Thuriot, Saint-Just, and Hérault deSechelles]
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 15 Oct. 1793; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 7)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Barère, Billaut-Varenne, Hérault deSechelles, and Robespierre, as well as the seal of the Republic, plus translation
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, n.d [1793]; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 8)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Barère, Billaut-Varenne, Carnot, Prieur [de la Marne], and Robespierre, about the requisition of a midwife
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, to the Commission des Monnaies, 7 February 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 9)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Carnot and Prieur de la Marne
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, to the Conseil général de la Commune de ?, 13 March 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 10)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Barère, Billaut-Varenne, Carnot, and Prieur de la Marne
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 9 April 1794; 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 6, Folder 11)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Barère, Billaut-Varenne, Carnot, and Prieur de la Marne,, plus translation
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 22 April 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 12)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Billaut-Varenne and Collot d'Herbois
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 4 May 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 13)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Billaut-Varenne, Collot d'Herbois, Prieur de la Marne, and Robespierre
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 9 August 1794; 1 leaf + 5 leaves (Box 6, Folder 14)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Billaut-Varenne, Collot d'Herbois, Eschasseriaux, Lindet, Prieur de la Marne, Robespierre, Thuriot, and Treihard. "Decrees that the representative of the people Frecine shall render himself without delay... to the parts of Belgium occupied by the French armies, to supervise transportation over there"; plus biographical notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 10 August 1794; 1 leaf + 3 leaves + 5 leaves (Box 6, Folder 15)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Collot d'Herbois, Eschasseriaux, Lindet, and Treihard; on the requirements of navigation on the Loire river; plus translation and notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 4 Sept. 1794; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 16)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Delmas, Fourcroy, Laloy, Lindet, Merlin de Douai, Thuriot, and Treihard; passport for Villaret, envoy of the French Republic to the Republic of Genoa, containing a physical description of him; plus translation
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 22 Oct. 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 17)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Bréard, Cochon, and Delmas, on the necessity to gather information on metal factories; plus notes about Bréard
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, to the People's Representatives at the Army of Italy, 2 sept. 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 18)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Carnot, Cochon, Delmas, Eschasseriaux, Fourcroy, Laloy, and Lindet, asking the representatives to collect and send exact informations on " all the officers and civils servants... whom it is important to know in particular [or] whose principles are justly suspected [...] The Committe must not leave you unaware of the growing number of general staff officers, which has increased to an extent detrimental to the public finance."
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 15 Jan. 1795; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 6 leaves (Box 6, Folder 19)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Bréard, Carnot, Chazal, Dubois-Crancé, Guyton de Morveau, Marec, and Prieur; on the payment made to entrepreneurs the Essone Canal extracting peat; plus translation, and notes on Carnot
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, to the Northern Army, 21 Febr. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 5 April 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 21)
      ALS in French, on the requisition of two hundred horses for the Police
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, to the National Treasury, 14 August 1795; 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 6, Folder 22)
      ALS in French, plus biographical notes on Thibault and Poisson
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public to the Peoples' Representatives in the Pas-de-Calais, 20 August 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 7 Oct. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 24)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Cambacérès, Carnot, La Revellière-Lépeaux, Marec,Merlin de Douai, and Sieyès, as well as the seal of the Republic; puts at the disposal of General Vezu "two hundred infrantrymen and two hundred cavalrymen for the purpose of protecting the arrival of a shipment of food for Paris."
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 11 august 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 26 April 1794; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 6, Folder 26)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of David, Dubarran, Jagot, Lavicomterie, Louis [du Bas-Rhin], and Voulland; on stolen horses seized from thieves who had raised a government warehouse; with translation and notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 24 May 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 27)
      ALS in French; on the arrest of a priest, "confesseur de Custine"
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 9 August 1794; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 28)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Amar, Bernard, David, Dubarran, Goupilleau, Jagot, Lavicomterie, Legendre, Louis du Bas-Rhin, Merlin de Thionville,Vadier, and Voulland; the Committe has examined the grounds for arrest of a former commandant of the "Batailon des Lombards"; with translation
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 10 August 1794; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 29)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Amar, Bernard de Saintes, Dubarran, Goupilleau, Legendre, Louis du Bas-Rhin, and Merlin de Thionville; the Committe decrees that Citizen Jean Pierre, shoemaker, shall immediately be released from jail; with translation
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 11 August 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 30)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Dumont, Goupilleau, Lacoste, Louis du Bas-Rhin, Merlin de Thionville, and Vadier; the Committe decrees that the Citoyen Paillard be judged by a militay tribunal
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 14 August 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 31)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Dubarran, Lacoste, Louis du Bas-Rhin, Merlin de Thionville, Vadier, and Voulland; the Committe decrees that the Citoyen Desmolin be released
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 30 August 1794; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 7 leaves (Box 6, Folder 32)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Amar, Bernard de Saintes, Dubarran, Dumont, Legendre, Louis du Bas-Rhin, Vadier, and Voulland; the Committee decrees the arrest of thieves captured on the Swiss frontier; with translation, and biographical notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 4 Sept. 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 30 Sept. 1794; 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 6, Folder 34)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Bourdon de l'Oise, Lesage-Senault, and Monmayou; on the restitution of money to a former prisoner; with biographical notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Salut Public, 14 Oct. 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 35)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Mathieu and Monmayou; on the necessity to monitor foreigners in Paris
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 24 Oct. 1794; 1 leaf + 7 leaves (Box 6, Folder 36)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Bourdon de l'Oise, Clauzel, Dumont, Lesage-Senault, Merlin de Thionville, and Reverchon; decrees a release from jail
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 14 Dec. 1794; 1 leaf + 4 leaves + 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 37)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Barras, Boudin, Garnier de l'Aube, Legendre, Lomont, and Meaulle; on the release from jail of ten people, including seven women, e.g. two former nuns; with translation and a portrait of Barras
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 28 Dec. 1794; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 38)
      ALS in French bearing the signatures of Mathieu and Monmayou, with biographical notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 14 March 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 14 March 1795; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 6, Folder 40)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Cales, Courtois, Gauthier, Sevestre, and Ysabeau
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 14 July 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 41)
      ALS in French, bearing the signature of Kervélégan, on the Citizen Prevost, released from jail
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 21 July 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 14 August 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 43)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Bailleul, Dailly, and Lomont
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, to the Administrators of Paris, 8 Sept. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 44)
      ALS in French, requesting information
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 8 Sept. 1795; 1 leaf + 6 leaves (Box 6, Folder 45)
      ALS in French, bearing the signatures of Bentabole, Bourdon de l'Oise, Clauzel, Legendre, Lesage-Senault, and Reubell; decrees that Baron, former administrator of the Dpt. of Finistère, be released from jail; with biographical notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 18 Oct. 1795; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 46)
      ALS in French, bearing the signature of Gauthier (surveillance in Gap), plus notice
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité de Sûreté Générale et de Surveillance, 29 Oct. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 6, Folder 47)
      ALS in French, bearing the signature of Cales, Delaunay, and Gauthier
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité des Finances, 24 Oct. 1794; 1 leaf + 3 leaves (Box 6, Folder 48)
      ALS in French, signed by Brisson, Cambon, Garos and Réal, plus biographical notes
    - France. Convention nationale. Comité des Finances, 24 Oct. 1794; 1 leaf + 3 leaves (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - France-Go (Box 7)
    - France. Département de l'Aisne, to a Chef d'escadron de la Gendarmerie, 28 Sept. 1800; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - France. Département de l'Aisne, sous-préfecture de Laon, 18 Nov. 1802; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 2)
      ALS in French: authorization to bear arms
    - France. Département du Calvados, district de Caen, 17 Oct. 1792; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 3)
      ALS in French: laissez-passer
    - France. Département du Cher, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - France. Département d'Indre-et-Loire, 6 June 1793; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - France. Département de la Loire-Inférieure, 15 Sept. 1805; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 6)
      ALS in French: notice of a death
    - France. Département de la Loire-Inférieure, 19 March 1796; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 7)
      ALS in French:: passport
    - France. Département de Marengo, 8 July 1803; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 8)
      ALS in French: letter from the Prefet to the Minister of War on transportation
    - France. Département de la Seine, n.d. [1799]; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - France. Département de la Somme, 6 May 1799; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 10)
      ALS in French: on local taxation
    - France. Directoire exécutif, 31 March 1797; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 11)
      ALS in French, on the revolutionary Army
    - France. Conseil d'administration [Board] de l'Hopital militaire de Lille, 9 May 1801; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - France. Inspecteur des Contributions du Département de Sambre et Meuse, 15 July 1799; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - France. Ministry of Finance, Februrary 1794; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Assignat de cinq cents livres(revolutionary banknote.)
    - France. Ministre of the Interior (Letourneur), to the Minister of Finance, 15 May 1798; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - France. Ministre of the Interior (Chaptal), to M. Barbé-Marbois, 4 August 1801; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - France. Minister of War (Schérer), 16 August 1798; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 17)
      ALS in French: appointment of Arnaud Baville as the new commander the Mayence army
    - France. Minister of War, 19 Oct. 1796; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 18)
      ALS in French, for the delivery of 830 horses to officers, signed by Daru; plus translation
    - France. Minister of War (Petiet), to Baville, 7 March 1796; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 19)
      ALS in French: new position for General Baville
    - France. Minister of War (Petiet), to the Minister of Finance, 11 July 1796; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 20)
      ALS in French: on the organization of ammunitions supply
    - France. Minister of Justice, 8 March 1811; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 21)
      ALS in French: nomination of a civil law notary in Fargeau (Loiret)
    - France. Minister of Justice, 14 Nov. 1800; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 22)
      ALS in French: nomination of a tax collector in Saverne (Bas-Rhin)
    - France.Minister of Justice. Bureaux des Prisons, 1803; 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 7, Folder 23)
      ALS in French: expenses for the Luxembourg Jail
    - France. Minister of the Navy, 7 Dec.1798; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 24)
      ALS in French: purchase of lighting poles
    - France. Minister of the Police (Sotin de la Coindière), 16 August 1797; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 25)
      ALS in French: radiation of a widow from the list of emigrés
    - France. Officiers de Santé du Quesnoy, 6 Dec. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - France. People's Representatives in the Départements de l'Ouest, to the Société Populaire de Maixent, 7 Dec.1798; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 27)
      ALS in French: on the necessity to monitor the distribution of the bread among the population
    - France. People's Representatives to the Italy Army, to the French Envoy in Genoa, 18 Nov. 1795; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 28)
      ALS in French: urgent need of money and shoes for the soldiers
    - France. Secrétariat général des Consuls de la République, 21 Sept. 1801; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - France. Trésorerie nationale, 22 July 1794; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - France. Trésorerie nationale, 9 Sept. 1798; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - France. Trésorerie nationale, 30 March 1803; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - France. Tribunal Révolutionnnaire, 1. January 1794; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 33)
      ALS in French: on Renaud-Philippe de Custine (guillotined on Jan. 3, 1794) and his wife, allowing them to communicate with each other, signed by Fouquier-Tinville
    - France. Tribunal Révolutionnnaire, 1794; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 34)
      ALS in French: on books and clocks left by detainees
    - François de Nantes, Antoine, to Citizen Vence, 18 Dec. 1802; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 35)
      ALS in French, plus translation and biographical notice
    - François de Neufchâteau, Nicolas-Louis, to M. Agasse, Printer and Bookseller, 1800; 1 leaf + 2 leaves + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 36)
      ALS in French: on his country-house, and his private library, plus translation and notes
    - François de Neufchâteau, Nicolas-Louis, to Napoleon I, 2 April 1805; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 37)
      ALS in French: thanks the Emperor for prolonging his tenure as President of the Senate
    - Fréron, Louis-Marie Stanislas [in his capacity as the owner of the journal "L'Année littéraire"], to the Abbot of Saint-Léger, 26 Aug. 1776; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 5 leaves (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Fréron, Louis-Marie Stanislas [as Representative on Mission to Provence], 1794; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 39)
      ALS in French: laissez-passer, plus translation
    - Fréron, Louis-Marie Stanislas, to Mme Chatenet, 23 May 1798; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Frochot, Nicolas, to the Receveur des Contributions, 23 Aug. 1804; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 41)
      ALS in French, plus notice
    - Fumel de Montségur, Philibert de, to M. de Saint-Just, 21 Nov. 1784; 1 leaf + 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 42)
      ALS in French, plus translation and notice
    - Garat, Dominique, to the Director of a Theater, 1795; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Garat, Dominique, to his tailor, 20 Oct. 1804; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Garat, Dominique, to M. Berger, 26 June 1811; 1 leaf + 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Garderat, General Jean, to the Minister of War, 1795; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 46)
      ALS in French: summary of his military career since 1764, and application for a pension, endorsed by Muller, Moncey, and Lannes
    - Garin Family, 1793-1809; 5 folders (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Garnier, Comte Jean-Baptiste, to Citizen Chiquard, 24 Febr. 1803; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Gaudin,Martin, to M. Dupuy (Département des Ponts-et-Chaussées), n.d. [1808]; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Gaudin, Martin Michel Charles, Duc de Gaëte, to Madame de Chambaudouin, dame d'honneur of the Princess Borghese, sister of Napoléon, 6 March 1807; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 50a)
    - Gay, Sophie, to M. Michelot (Intendant-General of Princesse Pauline Bonaparte), 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 50b)
    - Genlis, Stéphanie de, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 7, Folder 51)